Dominic J. Badolato Papers 2003.0137
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Inventory, undated, 1918-2003
  - AFSCME 17th International Convention Amendments and Resolutions (1968), AFSCME 19th International Convention Amendments and Resolutions (1972), AFSCME 20th International Convention Amendments and Resolutions (1974), ITT Hartford Life Employee Benefits (1995), and John Hancock Financial Services (1995), 1968-1995 (Box 100)
  - AFSCME (1950s), Connecticut Register and Manual (1959), Connecticut General Assembly (1960s-1970s), Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (1966-1971), Planning Committee (1967), AFSCME 17th International Convention (1968), Democratic State Central Committee (1968), Badolato mail (1970s), AFSCME (1972-1975), and Connecticut Register and Manual ( (1974), 1950s-1975 (Box 101)
  - AFSCME (1998-1999) (Box 102)
  - AFSCME (1980s-1990s) (Box 103)
  - AFSCME (1980s-1990s) (Box 104)
  - AFSCME (1990s) (Box 105)
  - AFSCME (1990s) (Box 106)
  - State of Connecticut Labor Department (1966-1967), Badolato mail (1967-1972), Connecticut State Labor Council (1970), Department of Agricultural Economics (1971), AFSCME (1971), Ella T. Grasso Inaugural Reception and Ball (1975), AFSCME (1978-1980), AFSCME (1995), and labor related newspapers (2001), 1966-2001 (Box 107)
  - AFSCME (1990-1993) (Box 108)
  - AFSCME Council 4 11th Biennial Convention (1985-1995) 4th National Labor Management Conference (1988) Connecticut Council 4 (1993-1995), Connecticut State AFL-CIO (1994), Dodd Washington Seminar (1995, 1997), 1985-1997 (Box 109)
  - AFSCME (1970s) labor related newspapers (1973-1975), Connecticut General Assembly (1974-1975), AFSCME 22nd International Convention (1976), public sector bargaining and strikes (1976), and Public Employees Department, AFL-CIO (1994-1995), 1973-1995 (Box 110)
  - 100 Years of Labor Legislation Conference (1967), Connecticut Department of Labor (1970s), AFSCME (1970s), voting districts (1970), Connecticut State Labor Council (1971-1972), Badolato mail (1972), National Commission on State Workmen's Compensation Laws (1972), public employee relations (1972), AFL-CIO (1973), Connecticut General Assembly (1973), labor related publications and bulletins (1973-1976), AFSCME International Executive Board (1975), State Government Journal of State Affairs (1976), Connecticut General Assembly (1976), Connecticut Labor's Bicentennial Conference (1976), AFSCME 22nd International Convention (1976), AFSCME International Executive Board (1977), 1967-1977 (Box 111)
  - Connecticut Council 4 11th Biennial Convention (1985-1989), Connecticut Council 4 (1987-1993) and Connecticut Council 4 12th Biennial Convention (1987-1990), 1985-1993 (Box 112)
  - AFSCME (1990s), Connecticut Council 4 (1994-1995), Reinventing Government in Connecticut (1994-1997), America Needs a Raise, AFL-CIO (1996), AFSCME International Executive Board (1996), and AFSCME Council 82 (1997) (Box 113)
  - AFSCME (1990s), 1980s-1990s (Box 114)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board Resolutions (1970), AFSCME International Executive Board (1970-1972), AFSCME (1971-1972), and Connecticut Conservation and Development Plan (1973), 1970-1973 (Box 115)
  - AFSCME (1970s), AFSCME National Leadership Conference (1977), AFSCME International Executive Board (1978-1979, 1981), Judicial Panel Chairperson's Report (1979), AFL-CIO (1981), AFL-CIO Regional Conference (1982), and Report of the Judicial Panel (1983), 1977-1983 (Box 116)
  - AFSCME (1990s), labor related publications (1990s-2000s), AFSCME International Constitution (1992), Connecticut State Board of Mediation and Arbitration (1999), AFSCME 34th International Convention Credentials Committee (2000), Badolato mail (2000-2001), Center for Connecticut Studies (2000-2001), Connecticut Conference of Municipalities (2001), and State Board of Labor Relations (2001), 1990s-2001 (Box 117)
  - AFSCME Executive Board (1984-1990) (Box 118)
  - AFSCME (1984-1990), 1992-1998 (Box 119)
  - AFSCME (1984-1990), 1992-1998 (Box 120)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1968, 1971-1972), 1968-1972 (Box 121)
  - AFSCME (1969, 1993-1996), AFSCME International Executive Board (1972), AFSCME 19th International Convention Resolutions (1972), AFSCME (1972-73), Connecticut State Senate (1993), 1969-1996 (Box 122)
  - AFSCME International Executive Board (1993), Judicial Panel Reports to the AFSCME International Executive Board (1993-96), and AFSCME International Executive Board (1995), 1993-1996 (Box 123)
  - AFSCME (1993-1997) (Box 124)
  - Badolato mail (1970s), AFSCME (1970s), and Badolato as Assistant Majority Leader (1975) (Box 125)
  - AFSCME (1960s-1990s) (Box 126)
  - AFSCME (1960s-1990s) (Box 127)
  - Badolato's appointments (1963-1966), AFSCME (1989-1997), and Badolato mail (2001), 1963-2001 (Box 128)
  - State Retirement Commission (1982-1984) (Box 129)
  - State Retirement Commission (1982-1984) and Connecticut Municipal Employees Actuarial Report (1983) (Box 130)
  - AFSCME (1986-1997) (Box 131)
  - AFSCME (1986-1997) (Box 132)
  - AFSCME (1987-1993) (Box 133)
  - AFSCME (1987-1993) (Box 134)
  - AFSCME (1989-1993) (Box 135)
  - Men Who Lead Labor (1937), White Collar (1956), Labor in America (1960), AFSCME (1958-1984), AFSCME (1989-1993), State of Connecticut Labor Laws (1993), Connecticut State Legislature (1995), and AFSCME (1997), 1937-1997 (Box 136)
  - AFSCME 18th International Convention (1970), AFSCME 12th Biennial Convention (1987), and AFSCME (1987-1993), 1970-1993 (Box 137)
  - AFSCME (1980s-1990s) (Box 138)
  - AFSCME (1980s-1990s) (Box 139)
  - AFSCME (1980s-1990s) (Box 140)
  - AFSCME (1990s) (Box 141)
  - AFSCME (1990s) (Box 142)
  - "Right Wing Machine" 16 mm color sound film reel (1978) unidentified 16 mm color film reel (1978) On the Record: Interview with Dominic Badolato VHS videocassette (1990), ITT Hartford VHS videocassettes (2) (1990s), AFSCME 1 inch video reels (3) (1995), National Conference of State Legislatures audiocassettes (13) (1995), and AFSCME Resolutions for the 32nd International Convention folder with a 3 ½ inch floppy disc "Voter Registration WordPerfect 5.1 dbadolato" (1996), 1978-1996 (Box 143)
  - Gelatin silver prints (34) and 120mm negatives (9) (1950s), gelatin silver prints, clippings, publications, and correspondence (1950s), metal plate impressed with Badolato's address (1955), gelatin silver prints (11) (1960s), Badolato gelatin silver prints and labor related newspaper clippings (1960s-70s), gelatin silver prints (1970s), color prints (1970s), 35mm film negative (1971), "The Connecticut Song" sheet music and 45 RPM 7 inch sound discs (3) (1974), AFSCME "After the Parades" 33 1/3 RPM 7 inch sound discs (3) (1978), 33 1/3 RPM 7 inch "Great Men of Music" sound disc (1979), AFSCME gelatin silver prints (8) (1970s-80s), gelatin silver prints (5) and AFSCME papers (1980s), 4 3/8 x 3 ½ color prints (23) (1990s), Christmas card and color prints (1995), AFSCME Council 4 color print, 8x10 gelatin silver print of Badolato, 8x10 color print of Badolato, 4x6 color print of Badolato, AFL-CIO political cartoon photos (5), Political Action Committee bag with AFSCME for Clinton pins (3), AFSCME Clinton pins (3), Solidarnsc pins (2), Stop Export of U.S. Jobs pin, Dodd Fowler DNC Dynamic Duo pin, "Crossroads: The Mine Workers Fight for Jobs with a Future" VHS videocassette, Say "NO" to NAFTA audiocassette, and a "Black Perspective - Campaign Profile" audiocassette, AFL-CIO gelatin silver prints and political cartoon prints with typed captions (6), 1950s-1990s (Box 144)
  - Ephemera: Dominic Badolato's Young Democratic Clubs of Connecticut State Convention Delegate ribbon with pin (1955), "DOMB" Connecticut license plates (2) (1959), AFSCME People and Jobs 1936-1976 pins (2) (1976), Bowl-O-Rink key chains, Elect Amenta Mayor pins (2), Paul Amenta for Mayor matches (4), Zander, Newman, Lima soap, Bowl-O-Rink matches, International Association of Machinists pin, International Association of Machinists pencil toppers (4), 36 inch "Zander for President" ruler, Zander and Lima stickers (5), election stickers, McGovern pins (3), McGovern President '72 pin, Labor for McGovern - Shriver '72 pins (2), Re-elect Ella Grasso pens (3), IAM (International Association of Machinists) pins (3), Get With It! IAM Member pin, McGovern tokens (3), Go Crow red feather, paper headband, yellow balloons (2), business card, and sticker, State and City Central Bodies sign, Labor Supports Nixon, Giaimo, and Lieberman sticker, Badolato name plate, gold Crucifix, San Jose Church token, keys (3), Connecticut State Labor Council AFL-CIO pocket knife, AFSCME token, Vote AFSCME pin, 50% of One pin, AFSCME Volunteer Organizer pin, unidentified gold pins (2), Loyal Order of the Moose pin, Connecticut Legislature "62" license plates (2) (* the number 62 refers to Badolato's seat in the Representatives Hall), Compliments of Mayor John L. Sullivan lipstick matches, Support HB 5869 pin, Handicap Awareness Day May 1 pin, PEOPLE pin, Elect AMENTA Mayor pin, AFSCME fabric patches (2), Connecticut State Employees Association Member pin, Connecticut Council 4 gift set, AFSCME membership booklets (2), AFSCME member stickers (4), and "Don't Jerry-Mander AFSCME VOTE NO" stickers (2), 1950s-1970s (Box 145)
  - Letter to Badolato from Lieutenant Governor Joseph J. Fauliso (1988), State of Connecticut General Assembly Official Citation in Recognition of AFSCME Council 4 50th Anniversary (1988), Badolato painted campaign sign, Grasso and Killian election signs and stickers, Clinton and Gore AFSCME signs (3), AFSCME Council 4 building illustrations, Re-elect Badolato book covers (2), "Ella for Governor New Britain Loves You" painted cloth banner, and Elect Paul Amenta Senator posters, 1980s (Box 146)
  - Property to be Annexed by the City of New Britain map, scale: 1" = 200' (1973), campaign posters (1980), AFL-CIO Centennial posters (3) (1981), City of New Britain Registrar of Voters map, scale: 1" =1000' (1982), Community Action calendar poster (1983), AFSCME Dukakis and Bentsen campaign posters (4) (1988), AFSCME Work Safety posters (5) (1990s), 25th PSI (Public Services International) World Congress posters (3) (1993), AFSCME posters (5) (1994), League of Women Voters of Connecticut 75th Anniversary poster (1995), AFSCME poster, Ella Grasso for Governor posters (3), Connecticut sign, and an AFSCME 14x22 inch sign with signatures, 1970s-1990s (Box 147)
  - Badolato's Notary Public Appointment Certificate (1955), Connecticut Port Authority Study Commission Final Report (1972), AFL-CIO Convention posters (3) (1995), Connecticut General Assembly Representatives Hall poster (DJB Seat 62, Section 1, Row 3), Mondale for America posters (2), AFSCME posters (2), AFL-CIO posters (8), Meeting in Session 14x11 inch sign, and an AFL-CIO poster, 1955-1995 (Box 148)
  - Newspaper clippings from the Hartford Courant and New Britain Herald concerning New Britain Politics and Labor Issues (1967) (Box 149)
  - Re-elect "Dom" Badolato State Representative posters (4), black and white posters (8), Representatives Hall map, Elect Congressman Ben Grabowski posters (3), Re-elect Badolato posters, U.S. Government Printing Office posters (1941), Connecticut signs (2), and Elect Mike Ferrucci sign, 1940s-? (Box 150)
  - Folded 48-star American flag, undated (Box 151)
  - Photographs: includes scenes of Dominic Badolato with labor union members, at the Connecticut General Assembly, and at political events. Most of the people and political figures are unidentified but there are some well known politicians, including Edward Kennedy, Ella Grasso, and Sargent Shriver, 1950s-1990s (Box 152)
  - Photographs, most unidentified but many showing DJB with groups of people, at political and labor functions, or posed with prominent people. Identifiable political and labor figures include Nancy Wyman), William Lucy, Toby Moffet, Sal Luciano, John Driscoll, Betty Tianti (first female president of a state labor federation), Richard Blumenthal, Michael Dukakis, Geraldine Ferraro, Al Gore, Lech Walesa, Jesse Jackson, and Nelson and Winnie Mandela; Slides -- two small boxes of DJB at political and labor functions (all other people unidentified); Transcript of the act to provide for unemployment disability compensation for Connecticut employees, introduced by DJB in 1973; transcript of a speech DJB gave in 1977 when he was reelected as Executive Vice President of the Connecticut State AFL-CIO; reports, photocopies of newspapers, and biographical information about Dominic Badolato, 1950s-2002 (Box 153)